Ashwin Shrestha

Phone: 9843729356 | Email: ashwinshrestha06@gmail.com

Linked In Profile: https://np.linkedin.com/in/ashwin-shrestha-7545a2101

Portfolio: https://ashwin773.github.io

Address: Kupandole, Lalitpur-01, Bagmati, Nepal

OBJECTIVE

My career has revolved around as an ios developer at ebPearls Pvt. Ltd. In the past two years I have also developed strong team work skills and interpersonal expertise that will be invaluable to my future employer. I make it my goal to create ios applications with the user in mind, and with a useable and intuitive user interface experience. I also understand the importance of creating highly readable and easily maintainable source code. I am constantly striving to learn new technologies and look to ways to better myself in this rapidly changing industry.

EDUCATION

Kathmandu University 2011-2015

Bachelor of Computer Engineering.

Orchid Public Higher Secondary School 2009-2011

HSEB in Science Faculty

Siddhartha Shishu Sadan 1998-2009

SLC

FREELANCED-PROJECTS

- Sastodeal (Swift Project): Sastodeal is one of Nepal's leading E-Commerce portal, one stop online store for genuine apparel, electronics, home & living and much much more. Available in IOS Store: Sastodeal
- HakuTV (Swift Project): HakuTV allows you to watch iptv streams from its server on your iPhone. Available in iOS Store: HakuTV
- Apex Digital (Swift Project): Apex Digital is iOS e-commerce app for one of the leading Smartphone Whole seller company here in Nepal, which will allow user browse smartphone products and buy. (Under development)
- TÜV SÜD (Swift Project): TÜV SÜD is an app which shows the latest development and testing phase a project is currently under of a customer, for an international service corporation focusing on consulting, testing, certification and training. (Under development)

EXPERIENCE

iOS Associate Team Lead at Electronics Business Pearls (ebPearls) Australia Pty. Ltd. January 2017 - Present

- + I have been recently promoted as an Associate team lead in ebpearls Pvt. Ltd.
- + Job:
 - To sub lead a team of iOS developers in the project assigned to.
 - Mentor new interns and trainee in basic knowledge of iOS app development.
 - Help in projects UI,UX, Code level in different projects if need be.

iOS Developer at ebPearls Technology Pvt. Ltd.

June 2015 - December 2016

- + I have been working at ebPearls Pvt. Ltd. an Offshore software company in Nepal as an iOS developer.
- + Achievement:

I have worked on some of the wonderful iOS application here at ebpearls and which has been successfully launched in iOS app store.

- 1. **Live Bid(Swift Project):** A real time live bidding platform where users can make offers and bid on different properties at auctions on the real estate market as they take place simultaneously from wherever their location. Available in app store: LiveBid
- 2. **Quint:** (**Objective-C**): Create own invitations when selecting from over 100+ contemporary designs with photographic backgrounds. RSVP tracking for each event invitation, regardless if the contact has the app or not. Create e-cards and share digitally on social media for free Available in app store: **Quint**
- 3. The city of Albany App (Swift project): The Albany App provides information to residents about Bins & Waste, Events, News and the ability to make payments and report issues. Albany app link

SKILLS

- **Programming Languages:** Swift, Objective-C, C, C++
- Web Skills: HTML, CSS
- Scripting Language: JavaScript, Structured PHP
- Database: MySQL
- Tools: Xcode, Apache, Eclipse, Netbeans, XAMPP
- **Technical:** Linux, Object Oriented Programming, Algorithm, Web Development.
- **Soft Skill:** Interpersonal expertise, Team work, Project Analysis.
- Project Management Tools: Atlassian(Jira), Trello, Zoho
- Version Controll System: Git

CUSTOM LIBRARIES

- **Photo-Video Selector:** An iOS (Swift) library (ViewController), which helps user selects video or photo, and picker type (camera, photo library or both). Available at: Photo Video Selector
- Custom Action Sheet Library: (Swift) Action Sheet library to give Spread out animation or Google like floating button animation with options. Available at: Custom Action Sheet

ACHIEVEMENT AND ACTIVITIES

- **Re-Nepal Hackathon 2015:** 1st runner up in Hackathon organized by Kathmandu Engineering College.
- LTSP Help Nepal: Volunteer for LTSP system deployment at Salyan, Nepal. (Year 2015)
- LTSP Help Nepal: Volunteer for LTSP system monitoring at 3 different districts (Saptari, Gaighat and Sunsari) of Nepal. (Year 2014)

REFRENCES

Dr. Bal Krishna Bal,

Assistant Professor,

Department of Computer Science and Engineering

Kathmandu University.

Manoj Shakya,

Assistant professor,

Department of Computer Science and Engineering

Kathmandu University.